<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM">
        <PMID Version="1">10684456</PMID>
        <DateRevised>
            <Year>2017</Year>
            <Month>02</Month>
            <Day>14</Day>
        </DateRevised>
        <Article PubModel="Print">
            <Journal>
                <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1940-4034</ISSN>
                <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
                    <Volume>2</Volume>
                    <Issue>3</Issue>
                    <PubDate>
                        <Year>1997</Year>
                        <Month>Jul</Month>
                    </PubDate>
                </JournalIssue>
                <Title>Journal of cardiovascular pharmacology and therapeutics</Title>
                <ISOAbbreviation>J. Cardiovasc. Pharmacol. Ther.</ISOAbbreviation>
            </Journal>
            <ArticleTitle>Pinacidil's Effects on Defibrillation Outcomes: Role of Increased Potassium Conductance Via the K(ATP) Channel.</ArticleTitle>
            <Pagination>
                <MedlinePgn>171-180</MedlinePgn>
            </Pagination>
            <Abstract>
                <AbstractText>BACKGROUND: It has been shown that the inhibition of potassium ion conductance decreases defibrillation threshold. We postulated that if potassium conductance is a primary mechanism affecting defibrillation threshold values, then increasing potassium ion conductance will increase defibrillation values. The primary objective of this study was to determine if the ATP-dependent potassium (K(ATP)) channel opener pinacidil would increase defibrillation threshold values. The second objective was to prove that the observed changes were due to potassium conductance by using the K(ATP) inhibitor, glyburide, to reverse the electrophysiologic actions of pinacidil. The third objective was to determine if the electrophysiology action sof pinacidil correlate with changes in defibrillation threshold value. METHODS AND RESULTS: Domestic farm swine (n = 14) were anesthetized and intubated. Subsequently, they were instrumented with monophasic action potential catheters and epicardial defibrillation patches. Defibrillation threshold values, action potential duration, effective refractory period, and ventricular fibrillation cycle length were determined at baseline and during treatment phase 1 and treatment phase 2. Pigs were randomized into 2 groups: group 1 (n = 6) received D(5)W in treatment phase one followed by D(5)W in treatment phase 2 and group 2 (n = 8) received pinacidil in treatment phase one followed by the addition of glyburide in treatment phase two. DFT(ED50) did not change at baseline, treatment phase one or treatment phase two for group 1 (10.5 +/- 2, 11.1 +/- 1.7, 10.5 +/- 1.0 J) or for group 2 (10.1 +/- 2.2, 11.4 +/- 4.2, 11.4 +/- 3.0 J). Electrophysiologic parameters )QRS, effective refractory period, action potential duration(90), and ventricular fibrillation cycle length) were not significantly changed from baseline in group 1. In contrast, effective refractory period, action potential duration(90), and ventricular fibrillation cycle length significantly decreased at all recorded sites after the administration of pinacidil in group 2 (range of 7-13%, 6-9%, and 12-17%, respectively). However, pinacidil did not change the basal level of dispersion in effective refractory period, action potential duration, and ventricular fibrillation cycle length during paced rhythm or ventricular fibrillation. Glyburide reversed pinacidil's electrophysiologic actions. CONCLUSIONS: Pinacidil does not alter defibrillation threshold, but it reduces effective refractory period, action potential duration, and ventricular fibrillation cycle length and does not increase electrical heterogeneity. Therefore, changes in potassium channel conductance as well as shortening repolarization are unlikely primary mechanisms for elevating defibrillation threshold.</AbstractText>
            </Abstract>
            <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Winecoff</LastName>
                    <Initials>AP</Initials>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>University of Georgia College of Pharmacy, Augusta, Georgia, USA</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                </Author>
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Sims</LastName>
                    <Initials>JJ</Initials>
                </Author>
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Markel</LastName>
                    <Initials>ML</Initials>
                </Author>
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Ujhelyi</LastName>
                    <Initials>MR</Initials>
                </Author>
            </AuthorList>
            <Language>eng</Language>
            <PublicationTypeList>
                <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
                <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
            </PublicationTypeList>
        </Article>
        <MedlineJournalInfo>
            <Country>United States</Country>
            <MedlineTA>J Cardiovasc Pharmacol Ther</MedlineTA>
            <NlmUniqueID>9602617</NlmUniqueID>
            <ISSNLinking>1074-2484</ISSNLinking>
        </MedlineJournalInfo>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
        <History>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
                <Year>1997</Year>
                <Month>7</Month>
                <Day>1</Day>
                <Hour>0</Hour>
                <Minute>0</Minute>
            </PubMedPubDate>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
                <Year>2000</Year>
                <Month>2</Month>
                <Day>23</Day>
                <Hour>0</Hour>
                <Minute>0</Minute>
            </PubMedPubDate>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
                <Year>1997</Year>
                <Month>7</Month>
                <Day>1</Day>
                <Hour>0</Hour>
                <Minute>0</Minute>
            </PubMedPubDate>
        </History>
        <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
        <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">10684456</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1177/107424849700200304</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pii">S1074248497000163</ArticleId>
        </ArticleIdList>
    </PubmedData>
</PubmedArticle>

</PubmedArticleSet>