<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="PIP">
        <PMID Version="1">12265591</PMID>
        <DateCompleted>
            <Year>1984</Year>
            <Month>03</Month>
            <Day>07</Day>
        </DateCompleted>
        <DateRevised>
            <Year>2016</Year>
            <Month>10</Month>
            <Day>21</Day>
        </DateRevised>
        <Article PubModel="Print">
            <Journal>
                <ISSN IssnType="Print">0020-7780</ISSN>
                <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print">
                    <Volume>122</Volume>
                    <Issue>4</Issue>
                    <PubDate>
                        <MedlineDate>1983 Jul-Aug</MedlineDate>
                    </PubDate>
                </JournalIssue>
                <Title>International labour review</Title>
                <ISOAbbreviation>Int Labour Rev</ISOAbbreviation>
            </Journal>
            <ArticleTitle>Population growth, inequality and poverty.</ArticleTitle>
            <Pagination>
                <MedlinePgn>443-60</MedlinePgn>
            </Pagination>
            <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Rodgers</LastName>
                    <ForeName>G</ForeName>
                    <Initials>G</Initials>
                </Author>
            </AuthorList>
            <Language>eng</Language>
            <PublicationTypeList>
                <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
            </PublicationTypeList>
        </Article>
        <MedlineJournalInfo>
            <Country>Switzerland</Country>
            <MedlineTA>Int Labour Rev</MedlineTA>
            <NlmUniqueID>9877781</NlmUniqueID>
            <ISSNLinking>0020-7780</ISSNLinking>
        </MedlineJournalInfo>
        <CitationSubset>J</CitationSubset>
        <MeshHeadingList>
            <MeshHeading>
                <DescriptorName UI="D003710" MajorTopicYN="N">Demography</DescriptorName>
            </MeshHeading>
            <MeshHeading>
                <DescriptorName UI="D004467" MajorTopicYN="N">Economics</DescriptorName>
            </MeshHeading>
            <MeshHeading>
                <DescriptorName UI="D008962" MajorTopicYN="Y">Models, Theoretical</DescriptorName>
            </MeshHeading>
            <MeshHeading>
                <DescriptorName UI="D011153" MajorTopicYN="N">Population</DescriptorName>
            </MeshHeading>
            <MeshHeading>
                <DescriptorName UI="D011157" MajorTopicYN="Y">Population Dynamics</DescriptorName>
            </MeshHeading>
            <MeshHeading>
                <DescriptorName UI="D011158" MajorTopicYN="Y">Population Growth</DescriptorName>
            </MeshHeading>
            <MeshHeading>
                <DescriptorName UI="D011203" MajorTopicYN="Y">Poverty</DescriptorName>
            </MeshHeading>
            <MeshHeading>
                <DescriptorName UI="D012106" MajorTopicYN="Y">Research</DescriptorName>
            </MeshHeading>
            <MeshHeading>
                <DescriptorName UI="D012959" MajorTopicYN="N">Socioeconomic Factors</DescriptorName>
            </MeshHeading>
        </MeshHeadingList>
        <OtherID Source="PIP">017666</OtherID>
        <OtherID Source="POP">00127966</OtherID>
        <OtherAbstract Type="PIP" Language="eng">
            <AbstractText>In this discussion of population growth, inequality, and poverty, the type of relationships that can be observed in intercountry comparisons are explored, reviewing the findings of several other authors, presenting some new estimates using an International Labor Office data bank, considering some basic conceptual problems, and examining some of the theoretical and empirical issues that call for investigation at the national level.  Intercountry comparisons, despite their limitations, appear to be the easiest starting point for empirical analysis.  The approach adopted by most researchers has been to select 1 or more population indicators and a measure of national income inequality and to explain intercountry differences in 1 or both of these variables in terms of each other and of other indicators of economic and social development.  Underlying this methodology is the assumption that there are aspects of demographic and economic change that are common to all countries included in the study, so that differences between countries give some guide to the likely evolution over time within any 1 country.  This can be accepted at best with reservations, but given the scarcity of data on the evolution of inequality over time, a working hypothesis of this type appears unavoidable.  But, as many of the factors likely to cause population growth and inequality operate over extended periods of time, a dynamic model is indicated.  A simpler model, which pays particular attention to lags and variations over time, may generate new insights.  A summary of the results of a new international cross-section analysis set up on these lines is presented.  Results suggest that contrary to expectations, reducing population growth does not seem to generate longterm benefits for the poor in this model, though some short term gains are found.  Increasing equality does appear to generate some decline in population growth, as well as persistent gains in incomes among the poor, but the reductions in population growth look small when set against the substantial reduction in inequality assumed.  The central problem is that inequality and poverty are complex variables conceptually and empirically.  3 major sets of issues are particularly relevant:  the nature of the unit of analysis; the reference period; and the conceptualization and measurement of welfare in relation to inequality and demographic change.  In interpreting empirical findings, it is necessary to be aware of the different aspects of inequality and the correspondingly varied links with demographic change.  The issues raised by the effects of inequality on population growth are distinct from those of population growth on the generation of inequality, and these are separated.  Future research possibly will be most productive if it concentrates on the multiple roles of population growth in the transformation of systems of production.</AbstractText>
        </OtherAbstract>
        <KeywordList Owner="PIP">
            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Demographic Factors</Keyword>
            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Economic Factors</Keyword>
            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">Literature Review</Keyword>
            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">Models, Theoretical</Keyword>
            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Population</Keyword>
            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">Population Dynamics</Keyword>
            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">Population Growth</Keyword>
            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">Poverty</Keyword>
            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="Y">Research Methodology</Keyword>
            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Socioeconomic Factors</Keyword>
        </KeywordList>
        <GeneralNote Owner="PIP">TJ: INTERNATIONAL LABOUR REVIEW</GeneralNote>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
        <History>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
                <Year>1983</Year>
                <Month>7</Month>
                <Day>1</Day>
                <Hour>0</Hour>
                <Minute>0</Minute>
            </PubMedPubDate>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
                <Year>2002</Year>
                <Month>10</Month>
                <Day>9</Day>
                <Hour>4</Hour>
                <Minute>0</Minute>
            </PubMedPubDate>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
                <Year>1983</Year>
                <Month>7</Month>
                <Day>1</Day>
                <Hour>0</Hour>
                <Minute>0</Minute>
            </PubMedPubDate>
        </History>
        <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
        <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">12265591</ArticleId>
        </ArticleIdList>
    </PubmedData>
</PubmedArticle>

</PubmedArticleSet>