<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
        <PMID Version="1">15717827</PMID>
        <DateCompleted>
            <Year>2005</Year>
            <Month>03</Month>
            <Day>29</Day>
        </DateCompleted>
        <DateRevised>
            <Year>2005</Year>
            <Month>02</Month>
            <Day>18</Day>
        </DateRevised>
        <Article PubModel="Print">
            <Journal>
                <ISSN IssnType="Print">1559-128X</ISSN>
                <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print">
                    <Volume>44</Volume>
                    <Issue>3</Issue>
                    <PubDate>
                        <Year>2005</Year>
                        <Month>Jan</Month>
                        <Day>20</Day>
                    </PubDate>
                </JournalIssue>
                <Title>Applied optics</Title>
                <ISOAbbreviation>Appl Opt</ISOAbbreviation>
            </Journal>
            <ArticleTitle>Titania, silicon dioxide, and tantalum pentoxide waveguides and optical resonant filters prepared with radio-frequency magnetron sputtering and annealing.</ArticleTitle>
            <Pagination>
                <MedlinePgn>378-83</MedlinePgn>
            </Pagination>
            <Abstract>
                <AbstractText>Mixing dielectric materials in solid-thin-film deposition allows the engineering of thin films' optical constants to meet specific thin-film-device requirements, which can be significantly useful for optoelectronics devices and photonics technologies in general. In principle, by use of radio-frequency (rf) magnetron sputtering, it would be possible to mix any two, or more, materials at different molar ratios as long as the mixed materials are not chemically reactive in the mixture. This freedom in material mixing by use of magnetron sputtering has an advantage by providing a wide range of the material optical constants, which eventually enables the photonic-device designer to have the flexibility to achieve optimal device performance. We deposited three combinations from three different oxides by using rf magnetron sputtering and later investigated them for their optical constants. Each two-oxide mixture was done at different molar ratio levels. Moreover, postdeposition annealing was investigated and was shown to reduce the optical losses and to stabilize the film composition against environmental effects such as aging and humidity exposure. These investigations were supported by the fabricated planar waveguides and optical resonant filters.</AbstractText>
            </Abstract>
            <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Rabady</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Rabi</ForeName>
                    <Initials>R</Initials>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering, Wayne State University, Detroit, Michigan, USA. rrabady@wayne.edu</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                </Author>
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Avrutsky</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Ivan</ForeName>
                    <Initials>I</Initials>
                </Author>
            </AuthorList>
            <Language>eng</Language>
            <PublicationTypeList>
                <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
            </PublicationTypeList>
        </Article>
        <MedlineJournalInfo>
            <Country>United States</Country>
            <MedlineTA>Appl Opt</MedlineTA>
            <NlmUniqueID>0247660</NlmUniqueID>
            <ISSNLinking>1559-128X</ISSNLinking>
        </MedlineJournalInfo>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
        <History>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
                <Year>2005</Year>
                <Month>2</Month>
                <Day>19</Day>
                <Hour>9</Hour>
                <Minute>0</Minute>
            </PubMedPubDate>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
                <Year>2005</Year>
                <Month>2</Month>
                <Day>19</Day>
                <Hour>9</Hour>
                <Minute>1</Minute>
            </PubMedPubDate>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
                <Year>2005</Year>
                <Month>2</Month>
                <Day>19</Day>
                <Hour>9</Hour>
                <Minute>0</Minute>
            </PubMedPubDate>
        </History>
        <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
        <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15717827</ArticleId>
        </ArticleIdList>
    </PubmedData>
</PubmedArticle>

</PubmedArticleSet>