<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
        <PMID Version="1">15884987</PMID>
        <DateCompleted>
            <Year>2007</Year>
            <Month>02</Month>
            <Day>07</Day>
        </DateCompleted>
        <DateRevised>
            <Year>2005</Year>
            <Month>05</Month>
            <Day>11</Day>
        </DateRevised>
        <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
            <Journal>
                <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1445-6354</ISSN>
                <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
                    <Volume>4</Volume>
                    <Issue>2</Issue>
                    <PubDate>
                        <MedlineDate>2004 Apr-Jun</MedlineDate>
                    </PubDate>
                </JournalIssue>
                <Title>Rural and remote health</Title>
                <ISOAbbreviation>Rural Remote Health</ISOAbbreviation>
            </Journal>
            <ArticleTitle>Hospital and after: experience of patients and carers in rural and remote north Queensland, Australia.</ArticleTitle>
            <Pagination>
                <MedlinePgn>246</MedlinePgn>
            </Pagination>
            <Abstract>
                <AbstractText Label="INTRODUCTION" NlmCategory="BACKGROUND">This article reports a study of patients and carers discharged from the Townsville General Hospital into rural and remote communities in north Queensland, Australia. The findings indicate the importance of focusing on the experiences of patients and carers in attempting to understand the impact of discharge procedures. The four stories and their implications exist within a particular healthcare context that impacts disproportionately on rural patients and their carers. Economic rationalism has shaped contemporary healthcare policy in Australia, creating a system that is encouraged to conform to market principles. The costs borne by individuals, groups and communities have been increasingly privatised. Later admission and earlier discharge from hospital is now the norm. Concern about the impact of this policy context on the lives of rural and remote patients and carers prompted the study, which aimed to: (1) examine, from the patient and carer perspective, the social, economic, cultural and emotional cost of hospitalisation away from home communities; (2) identify the needs of rural and remote patients and their carers before, during and after hospitalisation a long way from home; and (3) make recommendations for improved policies and practices concerning the continuum of care: from admission planning, through hospitalisation, discharge-planning, and post-discharge support, in the context of rural and remote location.</AbstractText>
                <AbstractText Label="METHODS" NlmCategory="METHODS">The experiences presented highlight the depth of the challenges faced by patients and their carers who live in rural and remote communities. Both quantitative and qualitative methodologies were used to obtain insight into the complexity of patients and carers' lives. The four vignettes presented in this paper are taken from in-depth, qualitative interviews with 12 patients and 12 carers.</AbstractText>
                <AbstractText Label="RESULTS" NlmCategory="RESULTS">The four stories described reveal the high financial and emotional costs, for patients and carers, of negotiating a healthcare system a long way from home. Challenges faced included inadequate admission planning, excessive accommodation and transport costs, and lack of post-discharge support services in home communities, as well as business failure, marital and family strain. There was an over-reliance on carers who lacked medical caring expertise, had other major commitments (family and work) and who may have had a tenuous and uncertain relationship with the patient.</AbstractText>
                <AbstractText Label="CONCLUSIONS" NlmCategory="CONCLUSIONS">Recognition of these complex circumstances, exacerbated by rural location, during the discharge planning process should mean that attention to ensuring patients and their carers are linked to adequate support services in their communities is of the highest priority. The communication and dissemination of information to patients and carers is also vital. Information on hospital admission, travel benefits, accommodation options, care requirements post-discharge are particular recommendations. To summarise, the experiences highlighted in this study suggest that patients and carers in rural and remote communities have not benefited from adequate discharge planning, and are struggling to cope in a policy context that encourages later admission, earlier discharge and over reliance on family and friends as carers.</AbstractText>
            </Abstract>
            <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Harris</LastName>
                    <ForeName>N M</ForeName>
                    <Initials>NM</Initials>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>School of Social Work and Community Welfare, James Cook University, Townsville, Queensland, Australia. Nonie.Harris@jcu.edu.au</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                </Author>
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Thorpe</LastName>
                    <ForeName>R</ForeName>
                    <Initials>R</Initials>
                </Author>
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Dickinson</LastName>
                    <ForeName>H</ForeName>
                    <Initials>H</Initials>
                </Author>
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Rorison</LastName>
                    <ForeName>F</ForeName>
                    <Initials>F</Initials>
                </Author>
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Barrett</LastName>
                    <ForeName>C</ForeName>
                    <Initials>C</Initials>
                </Author>
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Williams</LastName>
                    <ForeName>C</ForeName>
                    <Initials>C</Initials>
                </Author>
            </AuthorList>
            <Language>eng</Language>
            <PublicationTypeList>
                <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
            </PublicationTypeList>
            <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
                <Year>2004</Year>
                <Month>04</Month>
                <Day>02</Day>
            </ArticleDate>
        </Article>
        <MedlineJournalInfo>
            <Country>Australia</Country>
            <MedlineTA>Rural Remote Health</MedlineTA>
            <NlmUniqueID>101174860</NlmUniqueID>
            <ISSNLinking>1445-6354</ISSNLinking>
        </MedlineJournalInfo>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
        <History>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
                <Year>2005</Year>
                <Month>5</Month>
                <Day>12</Day>
                <Hour>9</Hour>
                <Minute>0</Minute>
            </PubMedPubDate>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
                <Year>2005</Year>
                <Month>5</Month>
                <Day>12</Day>
                <Hour>9</Hour>
                <Minute>1</Minute>
            </PubMedPubDate>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
                <Year>2005</Year>
                <Month>5</Month>
                <Day>12</Day>
                <Hour>9</Hour>
                <Minute>0</Minute>
            </PubMedPubDate>
        </History>
        <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
        <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">15884987</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pii">246</ArticleId>
        </ArticleIdList>
    </PubmedData>
</PubmedArticle>

</PubmedArticleSet>