<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
        <PMID Version="1">17241021</PMID>
        <DateCompleted>
            <Year>2007</Year>
            <Month>02</Month>
            <Day>28</Day>
        </DateCompleted>
        <DateRevised>
            <Year>2007</Year>
            <Month>01</Month>
            <Day>23</Day>
        </DateRevised>
        <Article PubModel="Print">
            <Journal>
                <ISSN IssnType="Print">0743-7463</ISSN>
                <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print">
                    <Volume>23</Volume>
                    <Issue>3</Issue>
                    <PubDate>
                        <Year>2007</Year>
                        <Month>Jan</Month>
                        <Day>30</Day>
                    </PubDate>
                </JournalIssue>
                <Title>Langmuir : the ACS journal of surfaces and colloids</Title>
                <ISOAbbreviation>Langmuir</ISOAbbreviation>
            </Journal>
            <ArticleTitle>Synthesis and &quot;schizophrenic&quot; micellization of double hydrophilic AB4 miktoarm star and AB diblock copolymers: structure and kinetics of micellization.</ArticleTitle>
            <Pagination>
                <MedlinePgn>1114-22</MedlinePgn>
            </Pagination>
            <Abstract>
                <AbstractText>Poly(N-isopropylacrylamide) (PNIPAM)-based tetrafunctional atom transfer radical polymerization (ATRP) macroinitiator (1b) was synthesized via addition reaction of mono-amino-terminated PNIPAM (1a) with glycidol, followed by esterification with excess 2-bromoisobutyryl bromide. Well-defined double hydrophilic miktoarm AB4 star copolymer, PNIPAM-b-(PDEA)4, was then synthesized by polymerizing 2-(diethylamino)ethyl methacrylate (DEA) via ATRP in 2-propanol at 45 degrees C using 1b, where PDEA was poly(2-(diethylamino)ethyl methacrylate). For comparison, PNIPAM-b-PDEA linear diblock copolymer with comparable molecular weight and composition to that of PNIPAM-b-(PDEA)4 was prepared via reversible addition-fragmentation chain transfer (RAFT) polymerization. The pH- and thermoresponsive &quot;schizophrenic&quot; micellization behavior of the obtained PNIPAM65-b-(PDEA63)4 miktoarm star and PNIPAM70-b-PDEA260 linear diblock copolymers were investigated by 1H NMR and laser light scattering (LLS). In acidic solution and elevated temperatures, PNIPAM-core micelles were formed; whereas at slightly alkaline conditions and room temperature, structurally inverted PDEA-core micelles were formed. The size of the PDEA-core micelles of PNIPAM65-b-(PDEA63)4 is much smaller than that of PNIPAM70-b-PDEA260. Furthermore, the pH-induced micellization kinetics of the AB4 miktoarm star and AB block copolymers were investigated by the stopped-flow light scattering technique upon a pH jump from 4 to 10. Typical kinetic traces for the micellization of both types of copolymers can be well fitted with double-exponential functions, yielding a fast (tau1) and a slow (tau2) relaxation processes. tau1 for both copolymers decreased with increasing polymer concentration. tau2 was independent of polymer concentration for PNIPAM65-b-(PDEA63)4, whereas it decreased with increasing polymer concentration for PNIPAM70-b-PDEA260. The chain architectural effects on the micellization properties and the underlying mechanisms were discussed in detail.</AbstractText>
            </Abstract>
            <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Ge</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Zhishen</ForeName>
                    <Initials>Z</Initials>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>Department of Polymer Science and Engineering, Hefei National Laboratory for Physical Sciences at the Microscale, University of Science and Technology of China, Hefei, Anhui 230026, China.</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                </Author>
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Cai</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Yuanli</ForeName>
                    <Initials>Y</Initials>
                </Author>
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Yin</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Jun</ForeName>
                    <Initials>J</Initials>
                </Author>
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Zhu</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Zhiyuan</ForeName>
                    <Initials>Z</Initials>
                </Author>
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Rao</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Jingyi</ForeName>
                    <Initials>J</Initials>
                </Author>
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Liu</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Shiyong</ForeName>
                    <Initials>S</Initials>
                </Author>
            </AuthorList>
            <Language>eng</Language>
            <PublicationTypeList>
                <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
            </PublicationTypeList>
        </Article>
        <MedlineJournalInfo>
            <Country>United States</Country>
            <MedlineTA>Langmuir</MedlineTA>
            <NlmUniqueID>9882736</NlmUniqueID>
            <ISSNLinking>0743-7463</ISSNLinking>
        </MedlineJournalInfo>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
        <History>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
                <Year>2007</Year>
                <Month>1</Month>
                <Day>24</Day>
                <Hour>9</Hour>
                <Minute>0</Minute>
            </PubMedPubDate>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
                <Year>2007</Year>
                <Month>1</Month>
                <Day>24</Day>
                <Hour>9</Hour>
                <Minute>1</Minute>
            </PubMedPubDate>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
                <Year>2007</Year>
                <Month>1</Month>
                <Day>24</Day>
                <Hour>9</Hour>
                <Minute>0</Minute>
            </PubMedPubDate>
        </History>
        <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
        <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17241021</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/la062719b</ArticleId>
        </ArticleIdList>
    </PubmedData>
</PubmedArticle>

</PubmedArticleSet>