<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
        <PMID Version="1">18950098</PMID>
        <DateCompleted>
            <Year>2012</Year>
            <Month>10</Month>
            <Day>02</Day>
        </DateCompleted>
        <DateRevised>
            <Year>2008</Year>
            <Month>10</Month>
            <Day>27</Day>
        </DateRevised>
        <Article PubModel="Print">
            <Journal>
                <ISSN IssnType="Print">1520-6106</ISSN>
                <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print">
                    <Volume>108</Volume>
                    <Issue>20</Issue>
                    <PubDate>
                        <Year>2004</Year>
                        <Month>May</Month>
                        <Day>20</Day>
                    </PubDate>
                </JournalIssue>
                <Title>The journal of physical chemistry. B</Title>
                <ISOAbbreviation>J Phys Chem B</ISOAbbreviation>
            </Journal>
            <ArticleTitle>Platinum nanoparticles generated in functionality-enhanced reaction media based on polyoctadecylsiloxane with long-chain functional modifiers.</ArticleTitle>
            <Pagination>
                <MedlinePgn>6175-85</MedlinePgn>
            </Pagination>
            <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1021/jp049336b</ELocationID>
            <Abstract>
                <AbstractText>Functionality-enhanced nanostructured matrices generated by intercalating polyoctadecylsiloxane (PODS) with octadecene (ODC) or octadecylamine (ODA) are employed as reaction media in which to grow Pt nanoparticles. Small-angle X-ray scattering (SAXS) signatures confirm that the amphiphilic PODS matrix orders into lamellae with a periodicity (d) of 5.24 nm, which corresponds to the siloxy bilayer and a double layer of alkyl tails. The regular packing of the hydrophobic tails becomes distorted upon introduction of ODC or ODA. Incorporation of K[(C2H4)PtCl3].H2O (a Zeise salt) into the PODS/ODC matrix, followed by reduction of the Pt ions by NaBH4 or H2, results in the localization of Pt compounds and nanoparticles along the siloxy bilayers, which remain dimensionally unchanged. Electron density profiles deduced from PODS/ODA, however, provide evidence for considerable structural reorganization upon metalation with H2PtCl6.6H2O. In this case, the siloxy bilayers broaden due to the presence of PtCl62- ions, and the hydrophobic layers become distorted due to the formation of (PtCl62-)(ODAH+)2 complexes. Subsequent reduction by NaBH4 restores the inherent PODS organization, while H2 reduction partially preserves the distorted matrix, indicating that some Pt nanoparticles form in close proximity to the siloxy bilayer. Transmission electron microscopy reveals that relatively monodisperse Pt nanoparticles measuring approximately 1 nm in diameter are located along the siloxy bilayers, whereas anomalous SAXS further indicates that nanoparticles form aggregates of comparable size to d within the PODS double layers.</AbstractText>
            </Abstract>
            <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Shtykova</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Eleonora V</ForeName>
                    <Initials>EV</Initials>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>Institute of Crystallography, Russian Academy of Sciences, Leninsky pr. 59, 117333 Moscow, Russia, EMBL, Hamburg Outstation, Notkestrasse 85, D-22603 Hamburg, Germany, Nesmeyanov Institute of Organoelement Compounds, Russian Academy of Sciences, Vavilov St. 28, Moscow 117813, Russia, Departments of Chemical Engineering and Materials Science &amp; Engineering, North Carolina State University, Raleigh, North Carolina 27695, and Department of Chemistry, Indiana University, Bloomington, Indiana 47405.</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                </Author>
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Svergun</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Dmitri I</ForeName>
                    <Initials>DI</Initials>
                </Author>
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Chernyshov</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Dmitri M</ForeName>
                    <Initials>DM</Initials>
                </Author>
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Khotina</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Irina A</ForeName>
                    <Initials>IA</Initials>
                </Author>
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Valetsky</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Peter M</ForeName>
                    <Initials>PM</Initials>
                </Author>
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Spontak</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Richard J</ForeName>
                    <Initials>RJ</Initials>
                </Author>
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Bronstein</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Lyudmila M</ForeName>
                    <Initials>LM</Initials>
                </Author>
            </AuthorList>
            <Language>eng</Language>
            <PublicationTypeList>
                <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
            </PublicationTypeList>
        </Article>
        <MedlineJournalInfo>
            <Country>United States</Country>
            <MedlineTA>J Phys Chem B</MedlineTA>
            <NlmUniqueID>101157530</NlmUniqueID>
            <ISSNLinking>1520-5207</ISSNLinking>
        </MedlineJournalInfo>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
        <History>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
                <Year>2008</Year>
                <Month>10</Month>
                <Day>28</Day>
                <Hour>9</Hour>
                <Minute>0</Minute>
            </PubMedPubDate>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
                <Year>2008</Year>
                <Month>10</Month>
                <Day>28</Day>
                <Hour>9</Hour>
                <Minute>1</Minute>
            </PubMedPubDate>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
                <Year>2008</Year>
                <Month>10</Month>
                <Day>28</Day>
                <Hour>9</Hour>
                <Minute>0</Minute>
            </PubMedPubDate>
        </History>
        <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
        <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">18950098</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1021/jp049336b</ArticleId>
        </ArticleIdList>
    </PubmedData>
</PubmedArticle>

</PubmedArticleSet>