<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
        <PMID Version="1">23282303</PMID>
        <DateCompleted>
            <Year>2013</Year>
            <Month>01</Month>
            <Day>04</Day>
        </DateCompleted>
        <DateRevised>
            <Year>2018</Year>
            <Month>09</Month>
            <Day>13</Day>
        </DateRevised>
        <Article PubModel="Print">
            <Journal>
                <ISSN IssnType="Print">1078-0998</ISSN>
                <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print">
                    <Volume>1</Volume>
                    <Issue>2</Issue>
                    <PubDate>
                        <Year>1995</Year>
                        <Season>Summer</Season>
                    </PubDate>
                </JournalIssue>
                <Title>Inflammatory bowel diseases</Title>
                <ISOAbbreviation>Inflamm. Bowel Dis.</ISOAbbreviation>
            </Journal>
            <ArticleTitle>Production and cellular source of interleukin-8 in ulcerative colitis.</ArticleTitle>
            <Pagination>
                <MedlinePgn>108-16</MedlinePgn>
            </Pagination>
            <Abstract>
                <AbstractText>: Evidence has accumulated that interleukin-1β (IL-1β) plays an pivotal role in mediating the inflammatory changes in ulcerative colitis (UC) and that interleukin-8 (IL-8) is responsible for some of the neutrophil-activating actions of IL-1β in vivo. We determined the IL-8 content and its cellular source in mucosal specimens of patients with UC, and analyzed whole gut lavage fluid on the presence of IL-8. In addition, we monitored these patients for a follow-up period of 1 year to see if IL-8 levels are indicative for colon at risk. Patients with active disease were enrolled; disease activity, endoscopical scores, and histopathological grading were assessed. Transcription and translation of IL-8 were demonstrated by in situ hybridisation and immunohistochemistry. Biopsy specimens from 30 UC patients and five controls were homogenized, and IL-8 content was determined. Lavage fluid from 10 UC patients and six controls was processed and analyzed for the presence of IL-8. Clinical events were monitored for a period of 1 year. IL-8 production was detected in both enterocytes and mucosal inflammatory cells. The mean IL-8 content in control biopsy specimens was 98.0 pg/mg (±10 pg/mg). The IL-8 content was 176.7 pg/mg (±21 pg/mg) in specimens obtained from noninflamed colon regions of UC patients, and 204 pg/mg (±27 pg/mg) in specimens taken from inflamed colonic areas (p = 0.023 and p = 0.013, respectively). The mean IL-8 levels in lavage fluid from UC patients was 36.4 pg/ml (±22.5 pg/ml) versus 3.1 pg/ml (±0.8 pg/ml) in control patients (p &lt; 0.05). Lavage IL-8 levels correlated with endoscopical score (r = 0.81; p = 0.009). During a follow-up period of 1 year, patients with high IL-8 levels in their noninvolved colon mucosa experienced more flare-ups than patients with low levels of normal mucosal IL-8. This study demonstrates that IL-8 is expressed in the normal large bowel mucosa. High levels are present in both macroscopically inflamed and noninflamed mucosa in UC. Both enterocytes and inflammatory cells contribute to the IL-8 production. Analysis of gut perfusate can be used to study IL-8 in UC, and IL-8 production in normally appearing mucosa in patients with ulcerative colitis may be indicative of colon at risk for inflammation.</AbstractText>
            </Abstract>
            <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Hommes</LastName>
                    <ForeName>D W</ForeName>
                    <Initials>DW</Initials>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>*Center for Hemostasis, Thrombosis, Atherosclerosis and Inflammation Research, and †Department of Gastroenterology, Academic Medical Center, University of Amsterdam, The Netherlands; and ‡Sandoz Forchungsinstitut, Vienna, Austria.</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                </Author>
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Radema</LastName>
                    <ForeName>S A</ForeName>
                    <Initials>SA</Initials>
                </Author>
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Jansen</LastName>
                    <ForeName>J</ForeName>
                    <Initials>J</Initials>
                </Author>
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Smit</LastName>
                    <ForeName>F</ForeName>
                    <Initials>F</Initials>
                </Author>
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Fockens</LastName>
                    <ForeName>P</ForeName>
                    <Initials>P</Initials>
                </Author>
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Zhao</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Y</ForeName>
                    <Initials>Y</Initials>
                </Author>
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Ceska</LastName>
                    <ForeName>M</ForeName>
                    <Initials>M</Initials>
                </Author>
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Tytgat</LastName>
                    <ForeName>G N</ForeName>
                    <Initials>GN</Initials>
                </Author>
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>van Deventer</LastName>
                    <ForeName>S J</ForeName>
                    <Initials>SJ</Initials>
                </Author>
            </AuthorList>
            <Language>eng</Language>
            <PublicationTypeList>
                <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
            </PublicationTypeList>
        </Article>
        <MedlineJournalInfo>
            <Country>England</Country>
            <MedlineTA>Inflamm Bowel Dis</MedlineTA>
            <NlmUniqueID>9508162</NlmUniqueID>
            <ISSNLinking>1078-0998</ISSNLinking>
        </MedlineJournalInfo>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
        <History>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
                <Year>2013</Year>
                <Month>1</Month>
                <Day>4</Day>
                <Hour>6</Hour>
                <Minute>0</Minute>
            </PubMedPubDate>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
                <Year>1995</Year>
                <Month>7</Month>
                <Day>1</Day>
                <Hour>0</Hour>
                <Minute>0</Minute>
            </PubMedPubDate>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
                <Year>1995</Year>
                <Month>7</Month>
                <Day>1</Day>
                <Hour>0</Hour>
                <Minute>1</Minute>
            </PubMedPubDate>
        </History>
        <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
        <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">23282303</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pii">00054725-199506000-00004</ArticleId>
        </ArticleIdList>
    </PubmedData>
</PubmedArticle>

</PubmedArticleSet>