<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="PubMed-not-MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
        <PMID Version="1">17397891</PMID>
        <DateCompleted>
            <Year>2007</Year>
            <Month>06</Month>
            <Day>05</Day>
        </DateCompleted>
        <DateRevised>
            <Year>2009</Year>
            <Month>11</Month>
            <Day>11</Day>
        </DateRevised>
        <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
            <Journal>
                <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1874-9968</ISSN>
                <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
                    <Volume>46</Volume>
                    <Issue>3</Issue>
                    <PubDate>
                        <Year>2007</Year>
                        <Month>Jun</Month>
                    </PubDate>
                </JournalIssue>
                <Title>Ultrasonics</Title>
                <ISOAbbreviation>Ultrasonics</ISOAbbreviation>
            </Journal>
            <ArticleTitle>DPSM technique for ultrasonic field modelling near fluid-solid interface.</ArticleTitle>
            <Pagination>
                <MedlinePgn>235-50</MedlinePgn>
            </Pagination>
            <Abstract>
                <AbstractText>Distributed point source method (DPSM) is gradually gaining popularity in the field of non-destructive evaluation (NDE). DPSM is a semi-analytical technique that can be used to calculate the ultrasonic fields produced by transducers of finite dimension placed in homogeneous or non-homogeneous media. This technique has been already used to model ultrasonic fields in homogeneous and multi-layered fluid structures. In this paper the method is extended to model the ultrasonic fields generated in both fluid and solid media near a fluid-solid interface when the transducer is placed in the fluid half-space near the interface. Most results in this paper are generated by the newly developed DPSM technique that requires matrix inversion. This technique is identified as the matrix inversion based DPSM technique. Some of these results are compared with the results produced by the Rayleigh-Sommerfield integral based DPSM technique. Theory behind both matrix inversion based and Rayleigh-Sommerfield integral based DPSM techniques is presented in this paper. The matrix inversion based DPSM technique is found to be very efficient for computing the ultrasonic field in non-homogeneous materials. One objective of this study is to model ultrasonic fields in both solids and fluids generated by the leaky Rayleigh wave when finite size transducers are inclined at Rayleigh critical angles. This phenomenon has been correctly modelled by the technique. It should be mentioned here that techniques based on paraxial assumptions fail to model the critical reflection phenomenon. Other advantages of the DPSM technique compared to the currently available techniques for transducer radiation modelling are discussed in the paper under Introduction.</AbstractText>
            </Abstract>
            <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Banerjee</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Sourav</ForeName>
                    <Initials>S</Initials>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>Department of Civil Engineering and Engineering Mechanics, University of Arizona, Tucson, AZ 85721, USA. sourav@email.arizona.edu &lt;sourav@email.arizona.edu&gt;</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                </Author>
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Kundu</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Tribikram</ForeName>
                    <Initials>T</Initials>
                </Author>
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Alnuaimi</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Nasser A</ForeName>
                    <Initials>NA</Initials>
                </Author>
            </AuthorList>
            <Language>eng</Language>
            <PublicationTypeList>
                <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
            </PublicationTypeList>
            <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
                <Year>2007</Year>
                <Month>02</Month>
                <Day>24</Day>
            </ArticleDate>
        </Article>
        <MedlineJournalInfo>
            <Country>Netherlands</Country>
            <MedlineTA>Ultrasonics</MedlineTA>
            <NlmUniqueID>0050452</NlmUniqueID>
            <ISSNLinking>0041-624X</ISSNLinking>
        </MedlineJournalInfo>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
        <History>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
                <Year>2007</Year>
                <Month>02</Month>
                <Day>15</Day>
            </PubMedPubDate>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
                <Year>2007</Year>
                <Month>02</Month>
                <Day>17</Day>
            </PubMedPubDate>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
                <Year>2007</Year>
                <Month>4</Month>
                <Day>3</Day>
                <Hour>9</Hour>
                <Minute>0</Minute>
            </PubMedPubDate>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
                <Year>2007</Year>
                <Month>4</Month>
                <Day>3</Day>
                <Hour>9</Hour>
                <Minute>1</Minute>
            </PubMedPubDate>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
                <Year>2007</Year>
                <Month>4</Month>
                <Day>3</Day>
                <Hour>9</Hour>
                <Minute>0</Minute>
            </PubMedPubDate>
        </History>
        <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
        <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">17397891</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pii">S0041-624X(07)00027-3</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.ultras.2007.02.003</ArticleId>
        </ArticleIdList>
    </PubmedData>
</PubmedArticle>

</PubmedArticleSet>
