<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM">
        <PMID Version="1">24233809</PMID>
        <DateRevised>
            <Year>2019</Year>
            <Month>11</Month>
            <Day>20</Day>
        </DateRevised>
        <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
            <Journal>
                <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1572-8773</ISSN>
                <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
                    <PubDate>
                        <Year>2013</Year>
                        <Month>Nov</Month>
                        <Day>15</Day>
                    </PubDate>
                </JournalIssue>
                <Title>Biometals : an international journal on the role of metal ions in biology, biochemistry, and medicine</Title>
                <ISOAbbreviation>Biometals</ISOAbbreviation>
            </Journal>
            <ArticleTitle>Pathogenetic role of magnesium deficiency in ophthalmic diseases.</ArticleTitle>
            <Pagination>
                <MedlinePgn/>
            </Pagination>
            <Abstract>
                <AbstractText>Magnesium is one of the most important regulatory cation involved in several biological processes. It is important for maintaining the structural and functional integrity of several vital ocular tissues such as cornea, lens and retina. The magnesium content of lens, especially in its peripheral part, is higher than that in aqueous and vitreous humor. Magnesium has also been shown to play critically important role in retinal functions. Magnesium plays significant role as a cofactor for more than 350 enzymes in the body and regulates neuroexcitability and several ion channels. Membrane associated ATPase functions that are crucial in regulating the intracellular ionic environment, are magnesium-dependent. Moreover, the enzymes involved in ATP production and hydrolysis are also magnesium-dependent. Magnesium deficiency by interfering with ATPase functions causes increased intracellular calcium and sodium and decreases intracellular potassium concentration. Such ionic imbalances in turn alter the other cellular enzymatic reactions and form the basis of the association of magnesium deficiency with ophthalmic diseases such as cataract. In presence of magnesium deficiency, an imbalance between mediators of vasoconstriction and vasorelaxation may underlie the vasospasm, which is one of the pathogenic factors in primary open angle glaucoma. Furthermore, magnesium deficiency is also a contributing factor in increased oxidative stress and inducible NOS stimulation that can further contribute in the initiation and progression of ocular pathologies such as cataract, glaucoma and diabetic retinopathy. In this paper we review the association of disturbances of magnesium homeostasis with several ophthalmic diseases.</AbstractText>
            </Abstract>
            <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Agarwal</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Renu</ForeName>
                    <Initials>R</Initials>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>Faculty of Medicine, Universiti Teknologi MARA, Sungai Buloh Campus, Jalan Hospital, 47000, Sungai Buloh, Selangor Darul Ehsan, Malaysia.</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                </Author>
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Iezhitsa</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Lgor</ForeName>
                    <Initials>L</Initials>
                </Author>
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Agarwal</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Puneet</ForeName>
                    <Initials>P</Initials>
                </Author>
            </AuthorList>
            <Language>eng</Language>
            <PublicationTypeList>
                <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
            </PublicationTypeList>
            <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
                <Year>2013</Year>
                <Month>11</Month>
                <Day>15</Day>
            </ArticleDate>
        </Article>
        <MedlineJournalInfo>
            <Country>Netherlands</Country>
            <MedlineTA>Biometals</MedlineTA>
            <NlmUniqueID>9208478</NlmUniqueID>
            <ISSNLinking>0966-0844</ISSNLinking>
        </MedlineJournalInfo>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
        <History>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
                <Year>2013</Year>
                <Month>10</Month>
                <Day>08</Day>
            </PubMedPubDate>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
                <Year>2013</Year>
                <Month>11</Month>
                <Day>01</Day>
            </PubMedPubDate>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
                <Year>2013</Year>
                <Month>11</Month>
                <Day>16</Day>
                <Hour>6</Hour>
                <Minute>0</Minute>
            </PubMedPubDate>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
                <Year>2013</Year>
                <Month>11</Month>
                <Day>16</Day>
                <Hour>6</Hour>
                <Minute>0</Minute>
            </PubMedPubDate>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
                <Year>2013</Year>
                <Month>11</Month>
                <Day>16</Day>
                <Hour>6</Hour>
                <Minute>0</Minute>
            </PubMedPubDate>
        </History>
        <PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus>
        <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">24233809</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1007/s10534-013-9684-5</ArticleId>
        </ArticleIdList>
    </PubmedData>
</PubmedArticle>

</PubmedArticleSet>
