<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2019//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_190101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="MEDLINE" Owner="NLM">
        <PMID Version="1">9427291</PMID>
        <DateCompleted>
            <Year>1998</Year>
            <Month>01</Month>
            <Day>27</Day>
        </DateCompleted>
        <DateRevised>
            <Year>2007</Year>
            <Month>11</Month>
            <Day>14</Day>
        </DateRevised>
        <Article PubModel="Print">
            <Journal>
                <ISSN IssnType="Print">0021-9533</ISSN>
                <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Print">
                    <Volume>110 ( Pt 22)</Volume>
                    <PubDate>
                        <Year>1997</Year>
                        <Month>Nov</Month>
                    </PubDate>
                </JournalIssue>
                <Title>Journal of cell science</Title>
                <ISOAbbreviation>J Cell Sci</ISOAbbreviation>
            </Journal>
            <ArticleTitle>The composition and dynamics of cell-substratum adhesions in locomoting fish keratocytes.</ArticleTitle>
            <Pagination>
                <MedlinePgn>2833-44</MedlinePgn>
            </Pagination>
            <Abstract>
                <AbstractText>Close contacts are the predominant type of cell-substratum adhesion in rapidly moving cells yet little is known about their composition and dynamics. To address these issues we have attempted to identify the molecular components of close contacts formed in rapidly moving fish epithelial keratocytes. In addition we have utilized the simple shape of keratocytes to explore the relationship between close contact formation and rapid locomotion. Beta1 integrin and talin molecules were found to be localized within a narrow rim of very close contact along the leading edge. These molecules together with vinculin were also found within small foci distributed evenly throughout the lamella, corresponding to regions of variable close contact. Alpha-actinin was found in foci within older, more posteriorly located regions of the lamella and along stress fibers. In addition to close contacts, small focal adhesion-like structures which stained positively for all antibodies tested were found at the tips of stress fibers within retracting cell margins. Interference reflection and total internal reflection microscopy of moving keratocytes showed cell-substratum contacts to be organized into distinct patterns that appear to move forwards, in concert with the leading edge. A feature common to all cells is a rim of very close contact at the leading edge. This region is specialized for the formation of new cell-substratum adhesions and is the site where patterns of close contact are generated. We have found that cell locomotion is most rapid when a uniform contact pattern is present but cell speed is progressively reduced as the contact pattern becomes more irregular. Furthermore, the local rate of lamellar extension is most rapid when underlain by regions of intermediate closeness to the substratum, but is reduced or ceases if the underlying contact is either very close or more distant, respectively. Our results suggest that close contacts and focal adhesions are related structures formed from a common hierarchy of molecular interactions. In addition the relationship between close contact formation and lamellar extension indicates a direct coupling between these two processes at the leading edge. Furthermore, we can explain the dynamic behaviour of close contacts in terms of the relative rates of trapping and release of component molecules that is initiated at the leading edge. We suggest that regulation of the molecular dynamics involved in leading edge specialization determines both the pattern of cell-substratum contacts and the net rate of actin filament assembly.</AbstractText>
            </Abstract>
            <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Lee</LastName>
                    <ForeName>J</ForeName>
                    <Initials>J</Initials>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>Department of Cell Biology and Anatomy, University of North Carolina, Chapel Hill, USA.</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                </Author>
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Jacobson</LastName>
                    <ForeName>K</ForeName>
                    <Initials>K</Initials>
                </Author>
            </AuthorList>
            <Language>eng</Language>
            <GrantList CompleteYN="Y">
                <Grant>
                    <GrantID>GM35325</GrantID>
                    <Acronym>GM</Acronym>
                    <Agency>NIGMS NIH HHS</Agency>
                    <Country>United States</Country>
                </Grant>
            </GrantList>
            <PublicationTypeList>
                <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
                <PublicationType UI="D013487">Research Support, U.S. Gov't, P.H.S.</PublicationType>
            </PublicationTypeList>
        </Article>
        <MedlineJournalInfo>
            <Country>England</Country>
            <MedlineTA>J Cell Sci</MedlineTA>
            <NlmUniqueID>0052457</NlmUniqueID>
            <ISSNLinking>0021-9533</ISSNLinking>
        </MedlineJournalInfo>
        <ChemicalList>
            <Chemical>
                <RegistryNumber>0</RegistryNumber>
                <NameOfSubstance UI="D015815">Cell Adhesion Molecules</NameOfSubstance>
            </Chemical>
        </ChemicalList>
        <CitationSubset>IM</CitationSubset>
        <MeshHeadingList>
            <MeshHeading>
                <DescriptorName UI="D000818" MajorTopicYN="N">Animals</DescriptorName>
            </MeshHeading>
            <MeshHeading>
                <DescriptorName UI="D002448" MajorTopicYN="N">Cell Adhesion</DescriptorName>
            </MeshHeading>
            <MeshHeading>
                <DescriptorName UI="D015815" MajorTopicYN="N">Cell Adhesion Molecules</DescriptorName>
                <QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName>
            </MeshHeading>
            <MeshHeading>
                <DescriptorName UI="D002465" MajorTopicYN="Y">Cell Movement</DescriptorName>
            </MeshHeading>
            <MeshHeading>
                <DescriptorName UI="D002478" MajorTopicYN="N">Cells, Cultured</DescriptorName>
            </MeshHeading>
            <MeshHeading>
                <DescriptorName UI="D005399" MajorTopicYN="N">Fishes</DescriptorName>
            </MeshHeading>
            <MeshHeading>
                <DescriptorName UI="D015603" MajorTopicYN="N">Keratinocytes</DescriptorName>
                <QualifierName UI="Q000166" MajorTopicYN="Y">cytology</QualifierName>
                <QualifierName UI="Q000502" MajorTopicYN="N">physiology</QualifierName>
            </MeshHeading>
        </MeshHeadingList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
        <History>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
                <Year>1998</Year>
                <Month>1</Month>
                <Day>14</Day>
            </PubMedPubDate>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
                <Year>1998</Year>
                <Month>1</Month>
                <Day>14</Day>
                <Hour>0</Hour>
                <Minute>1</Minute>
            </PubMedPubDate>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
                <Year>1998</Year>
                <Month>1</Month>
                <Day>14</Day>
                <Hour>0</Hour>
                <Minute>0</Minute>
            </PubMedPubDate>
        </History>
        <PublicationStatus>ppublish</PublicationStatus>
        <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">9427291</ArticleId>
        </ArticleIdList>
    </PubmedData>
</PubmedArticle>

</PubmedArticleSet>
